# Neelanshi Sharma

sharmaneelanshi00@gmail.com ns.github.io/portfolio ns-github14 in/neelanshisharma

Programming skills in Java, C and C++. Hands-on experience with Android Studio, Adobe XD, VS Code and Oracle. Leadership and management proficiency in event management and planning. Ardency for creative writing, culture talks and socializing.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur, Rajasthan

Jul 2017 – May 2021

Bachelor of Technology (Computer Science Engineering) CGPA: 8.79

### **EXPERIENCES**

### Heartfulness Institute, Hyderabad

Jul 2020 – Present

Frontend Development Intern

- Democratize web functionality for effective addition, update and deletion of elements in a website.
- Designed responsive components in React using Storybook and Office Fabric React UI.

### Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur, Rajasthan

Sept 2020 - Present

Project Trainee (Mobile Application Development)

- Full-stack development of a MedTrack using Android SDK and Google APIs.
- Designing frontend using XML and backend using Cloud Firestore in Firebase.

### Mayukh'20, Banasthali Vidyapith, Jaipur

Jan 2020 – March 2020

Sub Core Team Member (Team Workshop)

- Organized, regulated and managed tech and non-tech workshops on trending industrial subjects.
- Conducted interview for in-house workshops.

# COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

- Computer languages: C++, Java, HTML/CSS, SQL, Python, ReactJS
- Software: NetBeans, VS Code, Android Studio, NetBeans, Oracle, Storybook, Adobe XD, AWS
- Major Subjects: Android Application Development, AI and Machine Learning, Java, Data Communication and Networks, DSA, C++, OS Unix, Databases SQL & Oracle, Software Engineering SDLC

#### PROJECTS

# MedTrack – A pill reminder-appointment booking application

()

- Developing this app using Java in Android Studio and implements Android SDK and Google APIs.
- Responsive frontend layout using XML and backend using Cloud Firestore in Firebase

### GuacOn – A college meal planning application

G

- Integrating XML layouts and Cloud Firestore database in Android Studio using different dependencies.
- Creating API for faster and relevant retrieval of recipes and their details from the web.

### WILSAC – An event registration website for technical clubs in university

()

- Server-side programming using JSP enabling dynamic, platform-independent method creation.
- Maintained Apache Derby database and used JDBC API for CRUD operations.

## **CERTIFICATIONS & VIRTUAL EXPERIENCE**

- 1. Surface Computing, Data Analytics Workshop.
- 2. Overall **Technical Winner**, Mayukh'18 Technical Fest, Banasthali Vidyapith.
- 3. Android Application Development Certification.
- **4. AWS** Building Serverless Application by Coursera.
- 5. JPMorgan Chase & Co. Software Engineering Virtual Experience
  - Interface with a stock price data feed
- 6. Accenture Discovery Program
  - Project Priorities and Planning
  - User Journey Redesign & Client Communication
- 7. BCG Open Access Design Virtual Experience Program
  - Strategic Design

- Display data visually for traders
- Outcomes Analysis
- Prioritization & Impact Assessment
- Experience Design